let's recall the fundamental theorem of
calculus that we learned in kindergarten
so the formulation i'm going to take
here is that the integral
of a to b of f prime of x dx
is equal to f of b minus f of a
so if we look at the graph of f prime of
x the fundamental theorem of calculus
tells us that if we take two points a
and b then the area underneath
this graph is determined by the value of
another function namely
f at these boundary points alone
now a priori we need to know every point
between a and b
to determine the area but the
fundamental theorem of calculus tells us
that it's actually
only determined by the values of a
separate function namely its
antiderivative
at the endpoints now to get further
insight on the fundamental theorem of
calculus
what we'll do is we'll rewrite the
integral from a to b of f prime of x
dx as the integral over the closed
interval
a b f prime of x dx for us this is going
to be the same
and we'll also write f prime of x as df
dx
also write a b as the boundary
of the closed interval a b to denote the
boundary of a set
we use this partial symbol so the set
containing only the elements a b
is denoted by partial of the closed
interval a b
so now what the fundamental theorem of
calculus says is that the
integral over the closed interval a b of
df dx
is equal to the integral over the
boundary of the closed interval
of a b of f dx now just to make this
subsequent remark more transparent what
we can do is it can actually replace
df with partial f so from what we've
done here the way we've written the
fundamental theorem of calculus what we
see is that it's not that derivatives
and
integrals are the opposites of each
other it's that derivatives
are dual to the boundaries
of regions of integration and the
integral is the dual pairing here
you